DANIEL ANDRUS

Phone: (605) 269-1728 Email: danieleandrus@gmail.com Twitter Handle: @deaboy100 Github Name: Deaboy

PROFILE

I am an undergraduate college student at the South Dakota School of Mines and Technology. I have a passion for video games and technology, and my career goal is to become a developer in the games industry, the mobile application industry, or the desktop application industry. I grew up in Los Angeles, California, then moved to South Dakota in Summer, 2010. I attended Black Hills State University for two years before transferring to South Dakota School of Mines and Technology, where I plan to graduate with a bachelors degree of computer science in May, 2016 and immediately begin working in software or game development.

EXPERIENCE

INTERN DEVELOPER, 7400 CIRCUITS — SUMMER 2015 - PRESENT

I held an internship at 7400 Circuits, a circuit board company located in Rapid City. Here I worked to improve an existing an iOS and Android game called *Trouble with Robots*. I also worked on a cross-platform desktop application that interacted via USB with a handheld game cartridge reader and writer that allows users to create and play Neo Geo Pocket and WonderSwan games on their handheld game devices.

SDSMT PROGRAMMING TEAM — 2014 - PRESENT

In fall 2014, I joined the SDSMT programming team and participated in the ACM regional Programming Competition where my team finished 14th in the region out of over 285 competing teams and 1st in the school.

SERVER ADMINISTRATOR, PROGRAMMER — 2010 - PRESENT

Since 2010, I have owned and operated a public game server for which I and another developer have written hundreds of lines of server software to help manage the community. Through this, I have become greatly acquainted with Linux, SSH, and managing small communities.

WEB DESIGNER AND DEVELOPER, BLACKHILLS.COM — 2013 - 2015

In May 2013, I started working for a local web development company as a full-time web developer. The job entailed designing and building websites of diverse sizes and varieties. Many sites were for small businesses located throughout the Black Hills, but a few were for large, high-traffic businesses such as BlackHillsNews.com and Sturgis.com.

INTERN, FTW INTERACTIVE (NOW RED SHED TECHNOLOGY) — SUMMER 2012

I held an internship at FTW Interactive, now known as Red Shed Technology where I worked with experienced developers on mobile app projects. I gained experience working with server and client communications and data processing.

SKILLS

- Programming in the Java, C, C++, C#, PHP, Python, Objective-C, and Swift programming languages.
- · OS X, iOS, and Android development.
- Working with web technologies, including HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.
- Designing database systems using MySql
- · Working on team projects, object-oriented program design, and source control systems such as Git and Subversion

EDUCATION

Black Hills State University, Spearfish, SD — 2010-2012 South Dakota School of Mines and Technology, Rapid City, SD — 2012-2016

PERSONAL INFORMATION

I am good at math, am a fast learner, can pick up on new programming languages and standards quickly, and am a stickler for the proper usage of the word "literally". I can easily adapt to design patterns as well as programming paradigms and am perpetually learning the technologies and techniques employed in the software development, UX design, and games industries.

In my spare time, I enjoy playing and creating video games, creating YouTube videos, and learning more about the ever-changing technology industry. I love spending time with friends who enjoy similar things as I do. My career goals are to go into mobile application design and development, desktop application design and development, or game design and development. My ultimate personal goal with technology is to create applications that make people's lives better.

DANIEL ANDRUS

Phone: (605) 269-1728 Email: danieleandrus@gmail.com Twitter Handle: @deaboy100 Github Name: Deaboy

REFERRALS

Jim Carter — (651) 329-0064 — My supervisor at FTW Interactive.

Randee Peterson — randee@blackhills.com — (605) 641-5655 — My supervisor at BlackHills.com

Edward Mandy — ed@7400circuits.com — (952) 913-7611 — My supervisor at 7400 Circuits